David Jaffe

Web Design + Development

Bend, OR davidnjaffe@gmail.com 503-330-4656

Web and Graphic Design professional with over 10 years experience helping to create beautiful and powerful digital marketing assets for a variety of industries.

I have a passion for problem solving and strategizing through design, development and digital marketing. I have a well-rounded skill set that allows me to work precisely and efficiently across all types of platforms.

Work Experience

Web Designer

Odysys - Bend, OR June 2020 to Present

Design and build user friendly and mobile responsive websites for independently owned Bed & Breakfasts, Hotels and Inns. I work directly with the clients to provide a beautiful website while adhering to SEO best practices as well as ADA accessibility to the site.

Develop custom solutions to integrate clients reservation booking systems and other 3rd party applications.

Work on the production and maintenance of sites ensuring cross platform compatibility, performance and security.

Provide technical support to all clients.

Web Designer/Graphic Designer

Heliladder - Bend, OR March 2017 to Present

Design, implementation and maintenance of new and existing websites

Motion graphic production

Web Designer/Graphic Designer

Tiger Tugs - Bend, OR December 2016 to Present

Design, implementation and maintenance of existing website

Graphic Design Project Manager

Driving Force Graphics - Bend, OR April 2016 to February 2020 Design and produce a variety of specialized graphics and oversee the production and installation of larger scale projects.

Products include: Custom vinyl decals and vehicle wraps, CNC routed metal & wood signs, engraved wood and metal products, Flatbed UV printed products.

Manage shop employees on processing, installation and completion of vehicle wraps and decal installations.

Prepare customer files for print production and precessing

Collaborate directly with businesses of varying sizes to create specialized marketing products, including custom vehicle wraps, point-of-sale, signage, promotional items, brand logos, etc.

Guide clients through entire process, from conceptualization of design to production of the final product to ensure business objectives are met

Create custom logos and branding materials for small businesses, adapting designs as the business grows and/or market changes

Manage the creative assets for many businesses and create new marketing materials adapted for specific use materials.

Web Designer / Graphic Designer / Web Content Specialist / Digital Marketing

U.S. Outdoor Store - Portland, OR November 2009 to March 2016

Create digital graphics for website, blog and social media

Create in-store graphics, posters and retail signage

Prepare and optimize graphics and photos for website

Maintain and update page layouts and content on website

Assist with graphics and copywriting for print ads

Web production and daily maintenance of website

Produce and edit product and lifestyle photography

Assist in the design of the user interface for website

Manage social media advertising

Successfully developed digital marketing strategies and social media concepts resulting in continued growth of followers

Created digital lookbook all the way from concept to final product

Create graphics for promotional products

Major Accomplishments:

- Increase digital marketing budget by showing a strong ROI through increase of online conversions of online sales and email sign-up.
- Increase brand awareness through the creation of digital lookbook.

- Increase brand awareness through stronger social media strategy, increasing followers and social engagement.
- Contributed to the design of newer desktop and mobile website.

Graphic and Web Designer - Freelance

Blue Stem Designs - Portland, OR November 2013 to May 2014

Developed new branding for the landscape design firm with new logo, website and print promotional materials.

Graphic Designer - Freelance

Remote Wakeskates - Portland, OR January 2013 to March 2013

Designed graphics for the 2014 line of professional model wake skates. The designs were inspired by the hometowns of the athletes.

The wake skates are sold nationwide and can be seen in numerous media relevant to wake skating.

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

University of Oregon July 2020 to January 2021

Certificate in Digital Marketing Strategies

Portland State University - Portland, OR 2015 to 2015

Graphic Design

Art Institute of Portland - Portland, OR 2010 to 2011

BS in Marine Biology

Oregon State University - Corvallis, OR 2006 to 2009

Skills

- Photoshop, Illustrator After Effects, Lightroom Premier, Dreamweaver InDesign, Acrobat, Digital Photography, Photo Editing, Wordpress, Squarespace, Windows, Mac OS, Microsoft Office, Custom CMS, SignLab, ONYX, EnRoute (10+ years)
- HTML 5
- CSS
- · Graphic Design
- · Web Design
- Adobe Premiere

- User Experience (UX)
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- User Interface (UI)
- Copywriting
- Branding
- Video Editing
- Adobe Creative Suite (10+ years)
- WordPress (8 years)
- JavaScript
- Git
- Web Development
- Layout Design
- Content management systems (10+ years)
- Responsive web design (8 years)
- REST
- APIs
- jQuery
- MongoDB
- React
- GitHub
- Express.js
- Bootstrap
- MySQL
- Node.js

Links

https://davidjaffe.herokuapp.com/portfolio

https://github.com/davidnjaffe

https://www.linkedin.com/in/davidnjaffe

Certifications and Licenses

Digital Marketing Strategies

December 2015 to Present

Worked hands-on with local business's to strategize and implement digital marketing campaigns necessary for brand awareness and growth.

From this certificate I have adopted techniques necessary to prepare any business or organization for the digital world, including social media, digital media, digital marketing and strategizing.

Full Stack Web Development

January 2021 to Present

Successful completion of intensive Coding Bootcamp in Full Stack Web Development covering HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express, React, Node, MongoDB, MySQL, Git. Successful group projects coding and managing Git Repo & merging code.